#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ rachelmitchell333 (LinkedIn) builtinamerica.tv (Company)

Top Skills
Interior Design
Reality
Marketing Strategy

# Rachel Mitchell

Executive Producer TV/Documentaries the LONGEVITY series.com - BUILTinAMERICA.tv - Director of Programming ✓ #FOLLOW me for inspiration & to connect with all industries.

Delray Beach

# Summary

I have launched three national TV series and acquired sponsorship for 33+ episodes over the past 5 years. Our programming has aired on HISTORY Channel, H2, A&E, FYI (with Insight Television), and within FOX Networks. Our most recent productions have aired on FOX Business Network (with Elevate Media).

It is an honor to work with a team of EMMY, TELLY and AEGIS Award-winning Journalists, Producers, Directors and Scriptwriters. It is also a joy to help fund meaningful documentaries set to stream on Netflix. New episodes of "Built In America," "Innovation Nation," and "Sustainable Nation" are airing nationally this spring on Fox Business Network. Last year I worked for StarMedia on a special series "EARTH" with six-time Emmy Award Winning journalist John Holden.

The following was kindly written about me:

After consulting for companies around the world, Rachel works consistently to add value to organizations and feed her passions in life: funding and increasing sales for great companies that improve life, efficiency, green/ healthy living, technology, building, design, and giving back through philanthropic ventures.

She co-founded a successful private network to help other income property investors, design and stage their properties for selling and high-end leasing purposes. Interest in green technology and increasing the efficiency of properties, caused her to expand the business to help investors with alternative energy solutions.

She is quoted as saying: "It is an honor to work with executives & production professionals who have been successful for 20 years in television, and who have various shows that are currently on the air

in the business, technology, health, reality, cooking, lifestyle, & home improvement genres."

As a producer, Rachel brings sponsorship and creative elements to television shows that air nationally and video content that streams within multiple niche markets.

## Experience

Elevate Media

Executive Producer/ Director of Programming November 2019 - Present (10 months)

Creator of the "Innovation Nation" TV series and "Sustainable Nation" TV series

as apart of "Built in America" for airing nationally, streaming, and international syndication. Creating exciting content for airing within FOX networks.

#### **BUILTinAMERICA.tv**

It is an honor to join a team of executive producers who work on multiple national TV series and documentaries that stream on Netflix, and multiple platforms around the world. We have come together to honor great American innovation and progress!

The Longevity Group
Partner
October 2019 - Present (11 months)

StarMedia Productions, Inc.
Director of Programming/ Senior Producer
February 2019 - February 2020 (1 year 1 month)

As one of the lead producers of the National Television Series EARTH with John Holden on FOX Business Network, my focus is to share valuable solutions for people and our planet as a whole!

As Director of Programming I lend my support to multiple series for airing on different TV networks and streaming platforms.

Insight Television Productions, LLC Producer - Executive Producer

Page 2 of 3

February 2014 - January 2019 (5 years)

shows airing nationally on History Channel, within A&E networks, and FOX Networks

I launched the new season of "Built In America" by collaborating with Studio 1080; with a focus on technology, building, and manufacturing.

Specializing In:

Original Television Shows
Home Improvement Television Shows
Green Living Television Shows
Health and Lifestyle Television Shows
Documentaries
National Television Commercials

#### **HPS**

Co-founder/ Investor 2005 - January 2019 (14 years)

Toronto, Canada Area

helping others turn properties into profit income property staging & consulting film location staging & consulting interior and exterior design and consulting alternative energy solutions liaison - solar & wind energy

### Education

University of Toronto (1998 - 2001)